In that scenario with Aaliyah and David, she’s very fortunate to be able to have access to a board member to ask for that kind of advice.
Most of us don’t have that. So what can we do?
I actually suggest: just ring a friend, ask a colleague to help you out with some of these things.
Just like a good conversation doesn’t happen on its own, good delivery doesn’t happen on its own either.
And so there are lots of tips and tricks, where it can be about the basic things like room setup
or how you appear on the screen. But then it’s also about practicing some of that vocal delivery and trying on some of those different styles,
things that might be a little bit out of your comfort zone. Some people like practicing in front of a mirror.
Other people like practicing in front of a friend or a colleague who can give them some feedback,
because sometimes we’re just not aware of how we appear on screen or in a different setting.
And what might feel awkward to us might actually be really impactful or energizing to someone else.
Another great resource for practicing this skill can be a local chapter of Toastmasters, or even delivering an address at a local community group or place of worship.